[MUSIC]
[SOUND] The last major part of emberitic
cover is models.
Models are used to handle data that should
be saved permanently, either locally on
the browser or by making web requests to a
server that saves the information.
We'll start off by using JavaScript
objects that are saved in memory.
Then we'll switch to using Ember Data,
which is a library for
robustly managing model data in Ember
apps.
First we'll use Ember Data to save data in
our browser's local storage.
Then we'll see how to switch it to use
AJAX to save our data to a server.
We'll begin by using JavaScript objects
that will be loaded into memory.
You'd never actually build an Ember app
this way, but
it will keep things simple as we begin to
explore what models can do for us.
To start we'll define some sample blog
posts and
comments as JavaScript objects in a new
file called store.js or data store.
You can see here we have an array of posts
that contains
JavaScript objects with properties for id,
title, and body.
Then we have an array for comments that
contains JavaScript objects with an id,
a post id, and the comment text.
We'll add a script tag to our index.html
to include the data in our app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, I want to switch our posts route from
using the hardcoded post titles in
the template to using the post titles
loaded from
the JavaScript objects we're going to use
as models.
But first, let's revisit how the different
pieces of Ember fit together.
[SOUND] Remember when you visit a URL
Ember looks up the path from the router,
finds a match, and then loads a route that
loads a template, controller, and model.
By default a route loads a template and
a controller with the same name as the
route.
So the posts route loads the posts
template and the posts controller.
But there's no default for
what model gets loaded, so we have to
specify that ourselves.
Let's actually start off by writing a
posts route that
explicitly loads the posts template and
the posts controller.
Just so you can see what that looks like.
In our routes folder, we'll make a post.js
file.
We'll add a script tag for it to our
index.html.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then, in it,
we'll write Blogger.PostsRoute, quotes
Ember.Route.extend.
This should look pretty familiar to you
from writing controllers.
Here we take the app, the Ember app that
we've created.
We save a name of the route capitalized.
And then we add the word Route onto the
end.
We set that property equal to this object
where we've taken Ember.
We've invoked the route property.
We've called the extend method to subclass
the Ember.Route.
In here, we, we'll set the controller name
to posts.
And we'll tell it to render the template.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Again, this is the default behavior for a
route.
To use a controller and template with the
same name as the route.
But I wanna make sure you can see in code
exactly what's happening when you
visit a URL.
As I mentioned before, Ember has a heavy
emphasis on convention over configuration.
Ember chooses smart defaults for you, like
using templates and
controllers with the same names as your
routes.
And if you follow its conventions it will
do a lot of work without requiring you to
write much code at all.
Now, let's add a model to this route.
[NOISE] Here our model simply returns
the posts array we created in our sample
data.
By setting that array as the model for
this route it's now available in the
controller and template.
Lets use the model in the template.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
The each helper loops over each element of
the model,
which in this case is the array of posts.
For each post it repeats the content
inside the helper.
Inside the helper the context gets changed
so that attributes like title are called
on the current post inside of the each
rather than on the controller itself.
Now, let's take a look at our work in the
browser.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
There we go.
There are our post titles.
You might have noticed that even though we
set controller name
to posts in our route we never actually
made a posts controller.
If you don't create a controller of your
own Ember implicitly creates one for
you, and you might remember from way back
in the beginning of this course I told you
that a controller acts as a proxy between
a model and a template.
The implicit controller is set up to do
that proxying for you, automatically.
Templates never talk directly to models,
they always go through the controller.
Before we do another example,
let's take out the explicit setting of the
controller and template out of the route.
And if we go back here and refresh.
Sure enough, it works just as before.
Usually you won't need to override the
default choice of
controller in template for a route.
But if you do, now you know how.
Let's run through another example of using
an array as a model.
We'll make a recent comments route to show
recent comments on the site.
First, we'll add an entry to the router.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Next we'll make a route.
And we'll add a script tag to our
index.html.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
In the route.
We'll define it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here we'll choose our model.
Let's simply return comments.
Which, if we go back to our store.
There's our array of comments.
Let's update our application template to
include a link to our recent comments.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And finally, we'll create our template.
Before we forget, let's add it to our
handlebar's template loader.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And in the template, we'll display the
recent comments.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll display the text property of those
comments.
Let's check it out in the browser now.
[SOUND]
And there they are.