We've got a nice list of blog posts on our
home page now, but
we need a way to view an individual post.
In our data, in store.js, we give each
object a unique id.
A common practice is to put that id in the
URL to specify which post we want.
For example adding posts/3 to retrieve a
post with the id of 3.
Ember calls that 3 at the end,
a dynamic segment because it changes
depending on which post you wanna view.
Let's write a router entry for a route
with a dynamic segment.
[SOUND] We'll name the resource post,
for viewing a single post then we'll
customize the path.
But I'll start with posts, just like we
said we we're going to do here.
And then for the ID part put this colon,
write post_id.
Since this route is called post we know
that it
will automatically load the post template
and post controller.
We just need to make it load the post with
the given id to use as the model.
Let's make a route file called post.js.
Add a script tag.
And then create the route
and load a model.
And here we can include a parameter called
params.
What we can do is we can say return, grab
that array of posts.
We'll run the find by method.
And the fine by method, actually isn't a
standard JavaScript array method.
Member adds several methods to arrays, and
this is one of them.
And what we'll do is pass in id, so
that will look at the id property of all
of the elements in the post array.
And what it will look for is one that
matches params.post_id.
So here we have something new, the params
parameter in the model hook.
In our router, we added colon post id to
the end of the mapping for the post route.
That post id bit creates a property on
params called post_id whose value is the
number in the URL.
Here, for /post/3,
params.post_id will turn three, so the
model
will return the object in the post's array
whose id property's value is three.
In this case, or more generally, whatever
the number is in the URL right here.
Now that we've loaded the model,
let's add a post template, add it to our
template loader.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And in here, we'll write the title and
then the body of the post.
Let's also add links to each post from the
homepage.
We'll link to the post route, but
how do we know which post to link to since
there's a dynamic segment?
Well we can add a second argument to the
link two helper.
We can say this.id.
This refers to whatever post we're
currently looking at in the each loop.
And then we're just accessing the id
property.
So now it'll link to the post route with
this.id as the dynamic segment.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now, let's check our page in the browser.
We've got our links.
When we click them, we're going to the
right url.
But nothing's showing up on the page.
Let's see what we, if we can figure out
what we did wrong.
Oh, here we go.
We called this post.js instead of
post.hbs, let's rename this.
We'll refresh the page.
And there we go.
Now it works.
[SOUND]