While you're working on individual posts,
let's add the ability to edit them.
[NOISE] So put conditional.
They aren't editing.
Then we'll show the actual body.
We'll add a button [SOUND] with an action
that will trigger editing [SOUND].
So if they are editing, we'll have a form
for the editing.
[SOUND] Using our bootstrap class here for
form groups.
[SOUND] Standard label tag.
Here's where it gets interesting.
[SOUND] Just like a normal input tag we
have an id set equal to title.
Can add a class.
Now we say value equals title.
I'll explain exactly what this does in
just a moment.
So we can edit the title there.
Let's make it so we can also edit the
body.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay.
So here we've got this form and in general
it looks like standard HTML, but
the input tags are replaced with
Handlebar's input helper.
And in this case, the text area tag is
replaced with the text area helper.
Here inside the input helper, the value is
set equal to title.
And here, the value is set equal to body.
Notice these aren't in quotes.
By using the input helper, the data will
be bound to these properties.
In other words, when you update this
property in the template.
The property will automatically change on
the controller,
which will propagate it to the model.
If that's a little confusing, don't worry.
It'll make more sense when you see it in
action.
For now, let's add the Edit and Save
actions to our controller.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll need to include it in our
index.html.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Notice this is a little different.
Instead of saying Ember.Controller.extend,
I've said Ember.ObjectController.extend.
We'll talk about that in a moment.
So here, we've got the isEditing property,
we'll set it to false to begin.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So, all that our edit action does is just
set isEditing to true.
And all that our save action does, is set
isEditing to false.
Pretty simple.
If you're having a little bit of trouble
following the flow, that's okay.
Let's take a look at how this looks in the
browser now.
[SOUND] Choose a post.
Now we've got our edit button.
We can click edit, and then here's where
the magic happens.
If we change the title here, it changes up
here.
Remember that I said the input handle bars
helper bound the data to the property.
This is what I'm talking about.
When we change the data in one place it
automatically propagates throughout our
entire App.
And that's why the save button simply
toggles the isEditing controller property
to false.
The model object is updated as we type on
the page.
Let's go back and just take one last look
at that code, again.
So here, the input handlebars helper has a
value set equal to title.
That title property gets set on the
controller which propagates it
through to the model.
So when we change the value of the title
here it immediately gets changed on
the model, and since this reads the
property from the controller which
proxies it to the model, this gets updated
as we type.
Note that when we write a controller to
represent a model whose value is
a single object.
We use Ember.ObjectController.extend
instead of Ember.Controller.
Remember a template only communicates with
its controller.
And then the controller can communicate
with the model.
When the templates gets or sets a property
on an object controller,
it will pass that request to the model, if
the model has that property.
If you just use Ember.Controller,
the controller won't proxy information
between the model and the template.
You can try it out in our code to c.
If we change Ember.ObjectController to
just Ember.Controller.
Let's refresh here.
Now there's nothing on the page.
That's because here the title property is
being read from the controller.
But since the title property isn't set on
the controller, and the controller is no
longer proxying an object to use as the
model then the value of title is empty.
Let's change it back, so that our app
works properly now.
Similarly, we can make a controller for
our post's route using
Ember.ArrayController.
Let's end the ability to sort our posts by
their title.
[NOISE] In our posts template,
we'll add a link, with
an action to sort by title.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then in our controller, we'll define
that action.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here, when we set the sort properties,
property, on an array controller.
Ember will sort the array by the
properties you list.
If you wanna have them sorted by default,
you can set the property by default.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
You can also include multiple properties
if you want to sort by multiple values,
such as if we had a date and time
properties on our posts.
You can also include multiple properties
if you wanna sort by
multiple values such as if we had date or
time properties on our posts.
[SOUND] For now let's just take a look at
how that sort by title action works.
Well, while the posts are all ready
sorted.
Let's change their order inner store.js
file.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay.
Now if we click sort by title there we go.