Ember uses what's called the model view
controller, or MVC pattern, for
organizing your code.
There are an awful lot of implementations
of the MVC pattern.
So, if you're familiar with MVC from Ruby
on Rails, or BackBone JS, or maybe KoKo,
be prepared that just your understandings
of the term is how Ember uses them.
In Ember, templates describe how your user
interface looks.
They're written in the handlebar as
templating language,
which looks an awful lot like HTML.
In addition to normal HTML, templates can
contain
expressions like curly braces, title, end
double curly braces,
which allow you to insert dynamic
information into your pages.
Controllers define how your user interface
behaves,
based on information about the application
state,
such as whether something on the page is
showing or hidden.
And they use JavaScript methods to define
behavior,
such as popping up an alert when a certain
part of the page is clicked.
They also act as a proxy between your
templates and your models.
Models store data.
Any information that should stick around
after the page is refreshed, or
the browser is closed and reopened, get's
stored in a model.
If you're app stands alone by itself,
the model might store it's information in
the browser's local storage.
If your app is the user interface to a
backend web server,
then the model might store its information
through Ajax.
Routes load a model, controller, and
template.
For example, in our blogging app, the post
route might load
the post.hbs handlebars template, the
post.js controller, and
retrieve a particular blog post from the
back end database to be used as the model.
And finally, the router maps a URL to a
route.
So, if our app is at www.draculasblog.com
and we wanted draculasblog.com/posts/5.
To load the blog post with the idea of
five, we create an entry in
the router that mapped slash posts slash
five to the post route.