Before we can start building our blogging
app, we'll need to create our
directory structure, gather our
dependencies, and boot our Ember app.
To make it easier for you to get started,
I've set up a work space that comes with
all of the files and folders you'll need.
If you just wanna use the work space,
click the Launch work spaces button next
to this video.
I'd still recommend watching the rest of
this video though, so
that you can understand what everything is
for.
Let's start by setting up our project
directory.
We'll make a new folder called blogger.
I'm going to put it in my home directory,
but you can put it anywhere you like.
If you're using Windows or
Linux it might look a little different,
but you can follow along just the same.
In this blogger folder we'll make
folders for CSS, libs, routes,
models, controllers, and, templates.
Than we'll open this whole folder up in
the Sublime text editor.
Now, we'll also make a file called
index.html and
in it we'll make a bare bones HTML
document.
Now, we'll start gathering our
dependencies.
Ember uses semantic versioning to help you
identify the best version to use.
Here's how semantic versioning works.
Right now the latest version of Ember JS
is 1.7.0.
Let's say the Ember team finds a small bug
and wants to release a new version.
As long as all they do is fix that bug and
don't make any changes that could break an
app that depends on Ember,
they'll release the new version as 1.7.1,
incrementing the last of
the three version numbers, which is called
the patch version.
Now let's say that the Ember team has been
hard at work.
And they're ready to release a new version
with a bunch of awesome features.
So long as none of these features make
changes that can break an app that's built
with Ember 1.7.something, they'll release
the new version as 1.8.0.
Incrementing the middle of the three
version numbers,
which is called the minor version, and
resetting the patch version down to zero.
At some point, the Ember team will have
eventually built some
awesome new stuff that changes how things
work.
And they may also want to remove some
functionality that they
discover makes Ember slower.
At this point when they release a version
that breaks backwards
compatibility they'll change the version
to 2.0.0.
Incrementing the first of the three
version numbers which is
called major version and resetting the
minor and patch versions to zero.
I'm going to be using Ember 1.7.0 since
it's the most recent version, but
you should use whatever the latest version
of Ember 1.something.something is.
In other words, the latest version so long
as it's less than 2.0.0.
By sticking to a 1.something release, you
can be sure that as you follow along,
you won't run into anything that's
incompatible.
>> To download Ember, go to emberjs.com,
click on Builds,
then Release, and then the big Download
button.
If 2.0.0 or later has been released and
you need to find
the latest 1.something build, you might
need to go to Tagged releases to find it.
The other thing we need from the Ember
website is the handlebars library.
Back on the home page there's a handlebars
link.
Click it to download the handlebars.
We'll be using version 1.3.0.
So, if you're watching this video a while
after it was made,
make sure you're using the latest
1.something version.
Ember relies on jQuery, so we need to
download jQuery as well.
From jquery.com, we'll click the big
Download button.
And download the latest, uncompressed
development 1.something version.
Finally, I made a little library that
we'll use to
load our handlebars templates, called
Ember Handlebars Loader.
You can download it from the link in the
teacher's notes.
Here, it'll bring us to the repository.
Click the Library > Raw > File > Save Page
As.
Now, let's copy all of these JavaScript
libraries to our lib folder.
Then in our index.html file we'll
add script tags to put them in here.
[SOUND]
In addition to these
JavaScript libraries,
we'll also use
the Bootstrap framework
to style our app.
I'm going to be using version 3.2.0.
So once again, make sure you use the
latest 3.something.
We'll copy the bootstrap CSS into our CSS
Folder.
And then in our index.html, we'll add a
link for it.
[SOUND] Let's open our index.html page in
the browser to make sure there aren't any
errors.
We'll pop open the JavaScript console.
If we've mistyped something, you'll see an
error like I have here.
It says, file not found.
There I say, v.1.3.0.
It should just be v1.3.0.
And ember1.7.0 should be just ember.
Now, if I refresh the page, there we go.
No errors.
Now, the final thing we need to do before
we get started is to
create our actual Ember app.
We make a file called blogger.js.
And in it, we will write blogger equals
ember.application.create.
Back in our index.html, we will add a
script tag after our dependencies.
Then we will go back to the browser.
And refresh the page.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
If everything has gone right and
your Ember app has booted, you'll see a
blank page like this.
But in your JavaScript console, you'll see
something that looks like this.
These debug messages are printed by Ember
when it boots.
And it means that your shiny, brand new
Ember app is now ready for
you to start building on.
The last thing we need to do before
starting is to serve our
app with a web server.
This is necessary to load the handlebars
template starting in the next lesson.
There are a lot of ways to start a server
but
the easiest is to download Mongoose from
cesanta.com/mongoose.shtml.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then we can copy it into our project
folder.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And just double-click it to open it.
I'm gonna use the Cmd+Alt+J keyboard
shortcut to look,
to open my JavaScript console, and there
we go.
It's open in here.
If you see an error like this, where is
says something about bootstrap.css.map,
you can just go to your CSS folder, open
Bootstrap.
Go all the way to the end and then delete
this line.
Save the file, go back here, click
Refresh, and it'll go away.
If you're on a Mac and are comfortable in
the terminal,
you can also start a web server without
downloading anything at all.
Just open terminal.
Change directories to your project folder
and
run python -m SimpleHTTPServer.
Then in
your browser visit 0.0.0.0:8000.
Once again, if we
open the JavaScript console, we can see
that our app is running.
Now, with that, we're ready to start
building our Ember app.
The last thing we need to do before
starting is to
serve our app with a web server.
This is necessary to load the handlebars
templates starting in the next lesson.
There are a lot of ways to start a server,
but
the easiest is to download Mongoose from
the link in the teacher's notes.
Copy it into your project directory, then
open it up.
If you're on Mac and are comfortable on
the terminal,
you can also start a web server without
downloading anything at all.
Just open terminal, changer directories
into your project directory and
run python -m simplehttpserver.
Then in your browser, visit 0.0.0.0:8000.
And with that, we are ready to start
building our Ember wrap.
As you go through these videos, I strongly
suggest you take the following approach.
First, simply watch the video.
Don't bother taking notes or following
along,
just focus on getting the high level
understanding of the concept being taught.
Second, rewatch the video, pausing as it
goes and writing the code along with it.
This step will cement the nitty gritty of
how the code works and
start to ingrain your understanding.
Third, create a separate project.
And apply what I've shown you to your own
project.
For example, maybe make an app for an
animal shelter that shows
information about the shelter and a list
of animals available for adoption.
Take the ideas I cover in the video, and
then apply them to your own project.
It's this step where your deepest learning
will happen.
Start with this process now, rewatch this
video, following along.
And then, make the beginnings of your own
app.
[BLANK_AUDIO]