There's one annoying thing I wanna fix
before we move on.
If we load up our app.
Just the homepage here.
We just get a blank page.
Here's how we change that.
We'll open our router.
And then, since I want this to be the
homepage, I'll add path /.
Save it.
Then I'll refresh.
And there we go.
So what's going on here?
By default, the path to a page is the same
as the name of the entry in the router.
So for example, for our about route.
If we go here, the about path loads the
about route.
But we can override that by providing a
path explicitly.
Here, we've provided the path to the
homepage.
If we wanted to, we could overwrite it for
other entries too.
[SOUND] So now, if we go to about-us,
that won't work.
But if we add about-us, it will work.
It goes to the about route.
Or we could say something like path
get-in-touch.
Generally though, it's a good idea to pick
names for your routes.
It's the same as the path you'd like in
the URL.
So that it's easy to find things in your
code.
But for the root path, or
other special situations, you now know how
to override the default.
Except for that root path.
Let's switch it back to the defaults.
[BLANK_AUDIO]