The last concept we'll learn about the
router and templates is nesting.
What I wanna do is instead of showing the
phone and
email address on the contact page, replace
these with links for phone and email.
And if I click the phone link, it shows
the number over here.
And if click the email link, it shows the
email address over here.
Here's the completed feature, so you can
see what I'm talking about.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll start out by just building a new
page for phone.
Make a route.
[SOUND] And a template.
[SOUND] And then of course,
we'll load the template.
And we'll change our contact.hps template
to link to
the phone page in our future email page.
Now, let's check this out.
I'll refresh here.
oh.
Oh, we can't link to the route email until
we actually make it.
Let's go back.
We'll add this later.
[SOUND]
There we go.
We'll click phone and there it is.
Nothing new there.
You understand this by now.
But watch this.
Back here, we'll change the router, take
this and
we'll remove it for just a moment and then
we'll add this function.
This is what we call a nested route.
The last thing we need to do is in our
contact page,
we're gonna add a new handlebars helper.
Now, if we go back to our app, refresh the
page.
If we click phone, it shows up here at the
bottom of the screen.
That's right where our outlet helper is
gonna back up a second.
[SOUND] And we'll add the outlet handle
bars helper to our contact template.
Now, if we go back to the app, refresh the
page.
And we click phone,
the phone template gets rendered right
where that outlet helper is.
Anywhere that you add an outlet helper,
a nested route will get rendered into that
spot.
Finally, we can easily add two columns
using Bootstrap styles to
our page to get the desired layout.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And let's check it out.
There it is.
See how simple it is to make a nested
route?
That's one of the great things about
Ember.
It makes it really easy to create complex
use interfaces.
And you can even nest routes within other
nested routes.
Let's add that nested route for email now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Create our email template.
We'll load the template.
Gonna make it a little easier to read.
[SOUND] And now, if we go back to our app,
we need to add the email link.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Refresh.
Click email.
There we go.
Really easy.
And the email template gets loaded into
the outlet helper location as well.
As a gentle reminder, remember re-watch
this video and follow along.
As well as build out some nested routes on
your own app.
I'm gonna stop reminding you now, and just
assume you'll do so from now on.