Before we move on to controllers, l wanna
clean up some of our code.
On every page, we're adding the same Nav
bar over and over.
If we ever want to change that nav bar say
by adding another link or
maybe a logo on one side.
We'd have to change it in several places.
That's not good code.
Here's how we fix that up.
Or make a template called application.hps.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Add it, to our handle bars loader and then
in it.
Let me close a couple of these to make
things easier to read.
In it but all the stuff that's on every
page.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then an outlet helper.
And then on each one of these templates
I'm gonna remove all this extra code.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's take a look.
Still seems to work just fine.
So if you have this application.hbs
template
it's automatically loaded when your Ember
app starts up.
And then every subsequent template is
rendered into its outlet.
So now in all of our other templates we
don't have to have the Nav bar or
the div class container.
So to recap, when you visit a URL, the
router looks up the path and
matches it to a route.
The route loads a template with the same
name.
If the route is nested, the parent route
is loaded and
the child route is loaded into the outlet
helper of the parent.
There's also an implicit application route
that all other routes are loaded into.
If you create an application .hbs template
with an outlet helper all other
templates will automatically get rendered
into that outlet.
One thing you should get comfortable with
in Ember,
is the idea of convention over
configuration.
There's a lot of seemingly magical things
that Ember does for you.
Such as creating this implicit application
route.
These features are designed to let you
implement common patterns in your app.
Often without writing any code at all.
An important part of becoming an Ember
developer, is embracing convention over
configuration and following the path that
the Ember authors have laid out for you.