[MUSIC]
Up until now, all of our data has been
retrieved from
pre-built JavaScript objects loaded into
memory.
Most real apps need a more flexible data
store, where they can save and
retrieve information.
Usually, either client-side, using the
local storage HTML5 feature,
or server-side, using Ajax.
For both of these scenarios and many
others, Ember has
a library called Ember Data that makes it
much more pleasant to work with your
data by simplifying complex interactions
and automating repetitive tasks.
If you're using Workspaces, I've already
downloaded and
set up the following tools for you.
If not, you can down download ember data
from emberjs.com.
Click Builds.
And then tagged Releases.
And scroll all the way to the bottom and
find the link for tags/v1.0.0 beta 10.
And here it is.
And then save this file to your computer.
Because Ember data is still in beta, some
things might change slightly if you're
watching this video a while after I make
it.
So, I'd suggest you stick with the exact
same version I'm using.
At least until you get through these
lessons and
are more comfortable figuring out what may
have changed.
For most of these lessons, we'll use Ember
data to just save information locally on
our browser using local storage.
And so we'll need to get a local storage
adapter to use with Ember data.
From the link in the teacher's notes,
scroll down, click the local storage
adapter.js file.
Then raw and then save it to your
computer,
just like I've done here in the workspace.
Move both libraries into your apps lib
folder.
Ember data and the local storage adapter.
And add script tags for them in your
index.html.
Now, let's go into our store.js file.
Delete everything in it.
And we'll replace it with this code.
This simply sets up ember to use Ember
data with the local storage adapter.
[SOUND] Once again, blogger refers to our
Ember app.
And now we have something new.
DS, which stands for data store which is
how we call Ember data.
Now, let's go through our program and
update our code to use ember data instead
of plain old JavaScript objects.
First, unlike with plain old Java script
objects,
we need to define our models to specify
what properties they will have.
Here in our models folder, is where we'll
do that.
We'll start with a file called post.js.
We always use a singular word for our
model names in Ember data.
We will add a script data for this.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
In here, we'll write blogger.post for the
model name equals DS.model.extend.
This creates an Ember data model.
And then we'll specify the properties of
this new class.
It has a title and it has a body.
So to specify the properties of our model,
we pass in an object whose properties are
the properties of the new class.
The values are always DS.attr.
Let's make another model for our comments.
We'll create a file called comment.js.
[SOUND] Add a script tag.
[SOUND] And then we'll define the model.
[SOUND]
Very easy.
Note that for both models we didn't
include the ID property.
Ember data automatically sets it.
Now, let's update our app to use these
models.
We'll start with the model we return in
the posts route.
This .store returns
the data store which is Ember data's way
of referring to where we save things.
Then we call the find method and pass in
the name of the model as a string.
This will return every instance of the
post model.
Let's refresh our app and see if it's
working.
Check our JavaScript console for errors.
Error will processing route posts posts is
not defined.
Post.js line 3.
[SOUND] Oh,
I'm editing the wrong file.
Here I edited the post.js file.
I should have been editing the posts.js
file.
Let's copy this over to posts.js.
We'll save it, refresh.
There we go.
And you can see there's no posts being
displayed because we
haven't actually saved any into our new
Ember data local storage data store.
Now, let's update our recent comments
route.
[SOUND] Once again, this will return
all of the comments that we have in our
data store.
We'll refresh.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll click recent comments.
And there are no recent comments.
Now, let's work on displaying a single
post.
[SOUND] In a route, we'll make one change
to how we retrieve them.
[SOUND] It's almost the same as retrieving
every post object.
But here we've passed in a second
argument.
The ID of the post that we want to
retrieve.
That will return just that one single
post.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's go back here.
Refresh.
And it all seems to work.
In the next video, we'll see how to create
new posts so
that we can see more of the results of our
work