Let's add the ability to create new posts.
We'll start out by adding a new post route
[SOUND].
Then on our homepage, on the posts
template, we'll add a link to it.
And here, in the link to handle parse
[INAUDIBLE], if you want to add a class or
multiple classes to the HTML element,
we use class names as one of the
properties in the link to helper.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then we'll make a template,
[NOISE] It'll load it in our index.html.
[NOISE] And in the template, we'll have a
title of new post.
And then I'm just gonna copy the form from
when we're editing a post.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Pretty much the same thing.
So now we need to define this save action
for the new post controller
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And one descript tag for that
Now let's make the controller.
And we aren't gonna load up a model.
So we can just use the regular old Ember
controller.
Remember, our action was called Save.
So let's define that here [NOISE] so
we'll make a new post object.
Here's how we do that with ember data,
this.store.createRecord and
then the first argument will be the name
of the model that we want to create.
The post.
The second argument will be the value of
the properties.
So we'll have a title.
And the title we want to get from
the property that's set here on the
controller.
To do that, we run this get title.
Remember how in Ember, we have to set
properties using this dot
set rather than accessing directly That's
very similar to what we're doing here,
whenever we wanna get access to a
property.
Where as in regular Java Script,
we might just say this dot title in Ember
we have to say this dot get title.
So that Ember knows to update the value
when it's changed in
another part of the app.
Similarly, for the body, use the stop get
body.
So now we have our new post that's an
Ember data object, and
to save it into local storage, you just
run newPost dot save.
Before we do that, the object only exists
in memory.
This persists it to local storage.
Finally, we'll call this.transitionToRoute
('posts')
which is fairly self explanatory.
It'll transition our app to the posts
route.
Let's go and take a look at how this works
in our page.
[SOUND]
There we go.
It gets saved.
It shows up here we're transitioned back
to the posts throughout.
And if we refresh our app, it's still
there
because we've saved it into the browser's
local storage.
Now if we click on a post, you'll notice
that the IDs have
changed from being numbers to being funny
strings of letter and numbers.
That's just part of how the local storage
adapter works.
So don't worry about it.
The last thing we should do is allow users
to delete a post.
First, we'll update the post.hps template
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We'll add a button with
the action, delete.
Then, we'll define that action in our post
controller.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We wanna confirm before just deleting in
case the user
accidentally clicks the button.
[NOISE]
And if they are sure
look at the model and then we'll call
destroyRecord, which is
the ember data method to remove an object
both from memory and from local storage.
Then, we'll transition to
the post route and
let's check it out in our app.
Click Delete, say we're sure and it's
deleted