We haven't done much with our comments
yet.
I'd like a way to add a new comment to a
blog post and
to display all of the comments for posts
below the body.
Here's how it looks on the finished app.
To define a relationship like this in
Ember, we'll update our models.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here this line sets up
a property on each instance of post called
comments.
That returns all of the comments with that
posts ID.
ds.hasMany is an embered data method and
it makes the relationship with the comment
model.
Don't worry too much about the async
truebit here.
It's something that's going to become the
default by embered data 1.0 in
all likelihood.
Just know that you always need to include
it when you're defining a relationship
with the local storage adapter.
So, now post has a property called
comments that returns all of
the comments for that post.
We can also setup the other side of the
relationship.
We can make a post property.
This value is DS.belongsTo.
[SOUND] And now if you take a comment
object and
access the post property it will return
the post
whose ID matches the post ID stored in the
comment.
With our models set up let's update our
post.hps handle bars template to
use this new comments property.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[SOUND]
Here we're using the each handlebars
helper again, but this time we
don't wanna loop through the model itself,
but rather a property on the model.
All of the comments.
So we explicitly say the property name
that we want to loop through.
Now for
each comment we'll display a paragraph
with the text property of that comment.
Of course we don't have any comments yet
and we'll need a page for adding them.
We'll start with a router entry.
I want to display this on a post page so
I'm gonna make this a nested route.
[SOUND] Now, let's add a link to the post
template.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
So, we're linking to the new comment
route.
But, because it's nested inside here we
need to provide a value for
the dynamic segment.
You do that by passing in this.
Which refers to the model for the route
that we're currently on.
And then we'll extract the ID.
We'll add a little bit of styling.
Now when that link is clicked,
I want the new comment box to show up on
the bottom of the page.
So, I'm gonna add an outlet there.
Now, we'll need a template for the
new-comment route.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
We need to load this from our index.html.
Let's make this a subheading since it's
gonna be displayed within that
other route.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And we'll make a form for the new comment.
And we use the text area Handlebars
helper.
Bind it to the text property.
And add a submit button, and action his
name is save.
And then we'll need a controller to handle
the save action.
Run a script tag for it.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Define that save action.
Create a record for the comment.
The text will be the value of the text
property on the controller.
Then we'll save the comment.
But now we've run into a new problem.
Our new comment route is nested within the
post route and
we want to associate the comment with post
we are looking at.
But how do we get access to the post?
How can we find out what this post ID is?
When you need to access information in one
controller from another.
Ember provides a simple hook called needs.
In the needs hook you simple list any
controllers you need access to.
Here we've said we need the post
controller.
Now we'll move down and make use of this.
[SOUND] Thanks to the needs, we can get
the controller's property of the current
controller, and then get the post
controller and ask it for its model.
Next we'll make the association.
We'll ask the post for its comments.
And we'll call the pushObject method, and
pass in the comment that we just created.
And then we'll save the post.
And that's how you create an association
between two models in Ember.
Finally, we'll transition to,
the post's route for the post that we just
commented on.
Let's make sure this works in the browser
now.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's open our Java Script console.
Looks like we have a syntax error in
post.js line four and
comment.js line three.
So here in comment.js I've put a semicolon
where there shouldn't be one.
Probably did the same in post.
Yep.
That made it so our models couldn't load.
Let's refresh.
And now let's add a comment.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And there it is.