Most Ember apps interact with a backend
server using Ajax,
rather than just purely using local
storage.
For example, in a real blogging app, you'd
wanna save your posts to
a server where all your blog readers could
retrieve them.
You'd also wanna add authentication and
authorization, so only the blog owner
could create, update and delete posts.
And you might want to require users to
sign in before commenting.
Since this course is specifically about
Ember and
not about building backend servers, I'm
not going to
go into depth about how to build a backend
server to use with Ember.
But I will show you easy how it is to use
Ember with an already set up server.
If you don't know how to, I'd suggest
exploring Ruby on Rails or Python and
Django to learn how to create a backend
server yourself.
The rest of this video won't make much
sense if you haven't built a web
server with a API yet.
By default, Ember Data assumes that it
will store and
retrieve information through a backend
server using Ajax.
It will assume that your server provides a
JSON REST API.
Explaining the nuances of JSON and REST is
outside the scope of this course.
But if you aren't familiar with them, just
know that JSON is a standard format
in which data is represented in a similar
way to JavaScript object.
And REST is a standard way of using HTTP
verbs, like GET and
POST to represent what you want to do with
your data.
For this video,
I'm going to download my project from
WorkSpaces onto my local computer.
[SOUND] Like I mentioned in the first
stage,
I'll need to use a web server to run my
app.
[SOUND] So I'll copy Mongoose into
my App folder and open it up.
Now we have our app running locally and
we're ready to get started working on it.
I'm going to open up our code in the
Sublime Text editor for us to work on.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Since the rest adapter is the default
adapter for Ember Data.
To switch from the local storage adapter
to the rest adapter.
We can simply open our index.html, and
remove the local storage adapter from the
script tags, and store.js.
We'll save this, and refresh our app.
I'm gonna open up the JavaScript console,
so we can see what happens as we go.
So we'll refresh the app.
Down here, you can see that it says get,
I'm in the same
host and port that we're on and /posts 404
Not found.
That's because the route for the homepage
loads the model.
[SOUND] This.store.findpost which
retrieves all of the posts.
In a rest API, retrieving all of the posts
happens through a get request to /posts.
There's the /posts and there's the get.
And Ember data,
by default, makes the request to the same
host import as the app is running on.
Here to 192.168.1.86 port 8080.
Now, we could load up our back end server
app.
Let's say that it's running on local host
3000.
And configure Ember data to make requests
to local host 3,000 instead
of to 192.168.1.86 port 8080.
But browser security policies by
default prevent Ajax requests across
domains and ports.
There are ways around this using cross
origin resource sharing or cores.
But we'd have to configure cores, and it
doesn't work on older browsers.
The easiest way is simply to have our
backend app also serve up our Ember app.
I'm using Rails for my backend app.
And in Rails, I can simply copy the Ember
app into the Public folder.
And it will be served up as static
content.
If you're using a different backend app,
you'll have to move your files
accordingly.
Now, I'll fire up my Rails server.
[SOUND] My Rails server runs
on 0.0.0.03000.
I'm gonna make it so that we can see both
of these at the same time.
When I visit the homepage, since
index.html is in my public folder.
It gets loaded up, and my Ember app is
displayed.
After the Ember app loads and
this.store.find post is run,
you can see that the Rails server has
received a GET request for /posts.
Let's keep going through the app and see
how it interacts with the backend.
[SOUND] When we save a new post, it makes
a post request
to /posts to create the new record on the
backend.
Then, when the app transitions us back to
the post route,
it makes a get request to /posts again, to
retrieve all of the posts.
And here's our post.
When we clicked to view it, we can see it
here.
It doesn't trigger another request because
this post has
already been loaded from get/posts, which
loaded all of the posts.
But if we refresh the app so that all of
the data is cleared from memory.
Now, we can see that it makes the get
request to our
backend server to retrieve that post.
All of this is based on the conventions of
a JSON REST API.
Ember Data makes it really easy for
your client-side app to interact with your
backend.
If you build out a restful JSON API for
your backend, you can never write
a single line of persistence code and just
let Ember do all of the work.
And if you don't have control over your
backend server, perhaps because it's
already built, or because another team on
your project makes decisions about it.
There are ways to customize Ember data
adapters, so
that you don't have to right the same Ajax
calls over and over again.