[MUSIC]
Let's add some interactivity to our app
and
work on a feature where you can click a
button to trigger a pop-up.
As a reminder, we've been working with
templates,
which define how our application looks.
Now, we'll start working with controllers,
which define how our application behaves.
We'll start off by writing some HTML in
our template.
[SOUND] In Ember, if we want some kind of
action to be
triggered by clicking an element, such as
opening a pop-up,
we use the action handlebars helper.
Now, we define the action in the
controller associated with this root.
Let's make a new file called
controllers/about.js.
And in it we'll write our controller.
We define controllers as properties on our
main ember application.
Blogger.AboutController.
They follow a naming convention in which
the controller name must be
the capitalized version of the route name
with Controller added to the end.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Ember.Controller.extend creates a sub
class of the Ember.Controller class.
You get all the default behavior of an
Ember Controller plus any
additional behaviors you define.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Here, we're defining the showRealName
action,
which is going to pop up our alert.
Let's check out the results of our work in
the browser.
Here we have the error, nothing handled
the action showRealName.
That means that, somehow, we didn't define
our action properly.
Let's take a look at our code again.
Well, here's our action defined on our
controller.
It's the same as this action.
What we forgot to do was to add our
controller to our
index.html in the JavaScript script tag.
Now if we refresh our page, there we go.
It works.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Let's add an action to the contact page,
that lets users submit a secret message.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then we'll create a controller to
handle the action.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[NOISE] For now, we won't actually
do anything with the message since
we don't really have like a backend
server or anything to handle it.
Okay.
And then let's not forget to add this
index.html.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then let's take a look on our page.
Okay, there we go.
Now you know how to define actions and
ember controllers.