Popping up messages is all well and
good, but the real power of Ember is in
creating rich user interfaces.
As a step in this direction, let's add
actions that show and
hide a picture of Dracula on the About
page, like this.
[SOUND] We'll start by defining a property
on the controller.
[SOUND] Then in our template we can use
this property.
[SOUND] So
if the picture is showing,
that property is true,
then we'll show that image.
Otherwise, we'll show a button.
[SOUND] And that button will have an
action to show the picture.
[SOUND] Since, isPictureShowing,
is set to false in the controller.
[SOUND] The else branch in the template
will be shown.
Now, let's make our show picture action.
And make it so it will change the property
to true.
[SOUND] Changing a property on
a controller is as simple as running
this.set,
the property's name as a string and
then the new value that you'd like the
property set to.
It's important in Ember never to access
properties directly on an object
such as by writing something like
this.isPictureShowing equals true.
Don't do that.
Embers ability to observe changes and
automatically update them throughout your
application depends on using the .set
method.
Now if we go to our browser.
We can refresh the page.
Go to about.
Once again, we have that error.
Nothing hindered the action, show picture.
Let's see what we did wrong.
Notice this other error up here,
unexpected token in about js line ten.
It means I made a syntax error.
Sure enough, we can see I opened this
curly brace but I didn't close it.
[SOUND] If I add that closing curly brace
[SOUND] and refresh.
Now, let's look at the picture.
There we go.
What a scary guy.
This approach to updating the page is one
of the fundamental differences between
building a user interface in Ember and
using something like jQuery.
With jQuery you describe the steps needed
to
take the user interface from one state to
another.
To build this feature, we'd need to say to
show one of the elements of the dom, and
to hide another.
With Ember, you describe how your user
interface should look in various states.
And let Ember take care of making the user
interface look that way.
Let's add another button to the page to
hide the photo.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And then in our controller we'll define
this hide picture action.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And when we refresh our page, we can see
the photo and we can hide it.
[SOUND] Let's add a similar feature in our
contact page.
[SOUND] If the message has already
been sent we'll say thank you.
Your message has been sent.
If the message hasn't been sent.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Then we'll give them the option to send
the message.
In our contact controller we'll make a
property for
messageSent, set it to false by default.
And then once the message gets sent, we'll
switch the messageSent property to true.
[SOUND] And then let's take a look.
Make sure that works.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
There we go.
Sure enough.
Let's take this a step further and
print out a random confirmation number
after the message gets sent.
First go back to our template.
And we'll add-
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Now we need to set that confirmation
number in a controller action.
And we'll put it right here.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And we'll make it equal to a random
number.
Here you can see that a controller
property can actually get displayed on
the page.
Setting or updating it is as easy as using
this .set.
Just like with any other controller
property.
In a real app, of course, the confirmation
number would
probably be returned from a server where
the message was sent to.
We'll learn more about working with
servers when we start working with models.
For now, let's check out our feature.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
There's our confirmation number.
That just about wraps it up for
controllers.
To recap, the job of a controller is to
handle the display logic of
your application.
It provides two tools to help out with
this.
[SOUND] Properties, and actions.
Actions define some sort of behavior such
as opening a pop-up or
changing a property.
[SOUND] Properties can be displayed
directly on the page.
Or it can be used to determine
conditionals about what part of
the template is rendered.