[SOUND] Congratulations on getting through
this Ember JS course.
Ember's an amazing framework for building
web application user interfaces.
And by this time,
I hope you're comfortable with the basics
of building Ember apps.
The next step I'd suggest you'd take is to
go through the Ember guides.
The opening video on the guides, where
you'll build another blogging app and
the getting started walk through of how to
build a to do list will reinforce much of
what you've learned in these lessons,
as well as introduce you to some powerful
new tools.
Like computed properties.
Attribute binding in views.
I think you'll really enjoy learning about
them.
When you want to build a real Ember app,
where you care about things like
performance and deployment, you should
look into Ember CLI.
Ember CLI is a command line utility that
includes a server, build tools,
dependency management, and much more.
It has a bit of a steep learning curve,
but
it's the best way to build production grid
Ember apps.
Finally, one of the most frustrating parts
of Ember is when something goes wrong.
Often, the error messages are cryptic and
they don't always give you file names or
line numbers.
Searching online is often your best bet.
But ignore anything written more than a
year ago,
cuz Ember has changed dramatically since
then,
especially before its 1.0 version was
released on August 31st 2014.
For Ember data issues, don't look at
anything from before 2014.
Major changes were introduced at the end
of 2013.
When you have a question you just can't
find an answer to,
Stack Overflow is a great place to turn.
And give back on Stack Overflow by
answering questions for other people.
The Ember API documentation is another
fantastic resource.
Although like most API documentation, it
can be a bit hard to read.
And finally, the Ember forums are a great
place to learn and
discuss best practices and new features.
Ember.js bills itself as a framework for
creating ambitious web applications.
I hope you'll go and build something
ambitious now.